Finding Aid for the Harold Monro Papers LSC.0745
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Boxes 4-8: Harold Monro's Manuscripts
  - Notes for lecture on Poetry of Today and Tomorrow., Manuscript and typescript (17pp.). (Box 5, Folder I)
  - The Baron of Grogswill. Projected puppet play., (39pp.). (Box 5, Folder J)
  - Correspondence with the editors of The Rising Generation, Japanese periodical. (Box 5, Folder K)
  - Copies of issues of The Rising Generation containing articles by Harold Monro., (20 items). (Box 5, Folder L)
  - Dream Exhibition of a Final World. Working drafts., Manuscript and typescript with holograph corrections (47pp.). (Box 5, Folder M)
  - Poetry fragments, some with notes by Ezra Pound; and notes for poems., (90pp.). (Box 5, Folder N)
  - Prose fragments., Manuscript and typescript (60pp.). (Box 5, Folder O)
  - Selections for readings. Rough notes., Manuscript and typescript (24pp.). (Box 5, Folder P)
  - Arthurian Legend., (91pp.). (Box 6, Folder A)
  - Articles and notes for articles., Manuscript and typescript (56pp.). (Box 6, Folder B)
  - Essay on poetry., (6pp.). (Box 6, Folder C)
  - Essay on the poet., (14pp.). (Box 6, Folder D)
  - Goethe's connection with women. Lecture., (16pp.). (Box 6, Folder E)
  - Golden Temple. Projected play., (19pp.). (Box 6, Folder F)
  - Griffino. Story., Rough and corrected typescript and typescript carbon. (Box 6, Folder G)
  - Lecture notes on poetry--Georgian to modern., (33pp.). (Box 6, Folder H)
  - Lecture to the Heretics Society, Cambridge., (12pp.). (Box 6, Folder I)
  - Leviathan. Projected play., (19pp.). (Box 6, Folder J)
  - Miscellaneous fragments of poetry and prose., Manuscript and typescript (60pp.). (Box 6, Folder K)
  - One Day Awake, a Morality Play., (34pp.). (Box 6, Folder L)
  - Paper on Swinburne. Lecture before Caius Science and Art Society., (36pp.). (Box 6, Folder M)
  - Paper to the Heretics., Manuscript and typescript (14pp.). (Box 6, Folder N)
  - Poems., 93 poems. In notebook. (Box 6, Folder O)
  - Prose fragments., (45pp.). (Box 6, Folder P)
  - Samurai Press. Papers. Proposals for a voluntary nobility., Manuscript and typescript. 20 items. (Box 6, Folder Q)
  - Samurai Press. Creeds and correspondence (Maurice Browne, A.R. Greene, Harold Murray, J. Skilton, H.G. Wells)., 27 items. (Box 6, Folder R)
  - Essay on Wagner and Emerson., Manuscript and typescript (5pp.). (Box 6, Folder S)
  - Wordsworth Revisited., Manuscript and typescript (25pp.). (Box 6, Folder T)
  - The Younger Poets. Article., (7pp.). (Box 6, Folder U)
  - Jehovah. Projected epic. Three versions., (150pp.). (Box 6, Folder V)
  - Biographic Notes On Being A socialist., Typescript (2pp.). (Box 7, Folder A)
  - Can Any Religion Meet the Conditions of Modern Civilization? Lecture., Manuscript and typescript (17pp.). (Box 7, Folder B)
  - Cophetua. Projected play in verse., (44pp.). (Box 7, Folder C)
  - The Cricket Girl. One-act farce. Juvenilia., Typescript (16pp.). (Box 7, Folder D)
  - The Doctrine of Individual Immortality. Essay., (3pp.). (Box 7, Folder E)
  - Epic of the Age. Prose notes., (9pp.). (Box 7, Folder G)
  - Fate. Prose. Juvenilia., (2pp.). (Box 7, Folder H)
  - Fate and The Garden. Poems., (10pp.). (Box 7, Folder I)
  - Florentine Evening., (4pp.). (Box 7, Folder J)
  - The God Myth in Modern Poetry. Lecture notes., Typescript (25pp.). (Box 7, Folder K)
  - Jean-Marie. [translated from the French by Harold Monro] Play. Juvenilia., Typescript (34pp.). (Box 7, Folder L)
  - John Davidson. Article., Manuscript and typescript (24pp.). (Box 7, Folder M)
  - Lyrics. Juvenilia., Autographed manuscript and typescript (34pp.). (Box 7, Folder N)
  - Nature and Functions of Poetry. Lecture., (22pp.). (Box 7, Folder O)
  - Field Excursion., (2pp.). (Box 7, Folder P)
  - From An Old House., (1p.). (Box 7, Folder P)
    Poetry.
  - Street Fight., (3pp.). (Box 7, Folder P)
  - Any Man's Daughter., Autographed (2pp.). (Box 7, Folder P)
  - Silence Between., Autographed (1p.). (Box 7, Folder P)
  - Unknown Country., Autographed (2pp.). (Box 7, Folder P)
  - The Earth for Sale., Autographed (2pp.). (Box 7, Folder P)
  - Moonlit Beach., Autographed (2pp.). (Box 7, Folder P)
  - The Trees., (5pp.). (Box 7, Folder P)
  - Elegy., Autographed (2pp.). (Box 7, Folder P)
  - Miscellaneous fragments., (3pp.). (Box 7, Folder P)
  - The Man of Wisdom and His Treasure. Fantasy. Juvenilia., Typescript (5pp.). (Box 7, Folder Q)
  - Jacques and I. Sketch. Juvenilia., Typescript (4pp.). (Box 7, Folder Q)
    Prose Sketches.
  - The Ideal Air-bath. Article. Juvenilia., Typescript (4pp.). (Box 7, Folder Q)
  - A Modern Hermit. Juvenilia., Manuscript and typescript (11pp.). (Box 7, Folder Q)
  - The Fishermen. Sketch. Juvenilia., Typescript (6pp.). (Box 7, Folder Q)
  - Concerning Steam-rollers. Juvenilia., Typescript (4pp.). (Box 7, Folder Q)
  - The Real Competence. Article., (5pp.). (Box 7, Folder R)
  - The Real God. Essay., (2pp.). (Box 7, Folder R)
  - Rex Vitae. Poem., (3pp.). (Box 7, Folder R)
  - Socialism and the Simplication of Life. Essay., (39pp.). (Box 7, Folder R)
  - Stories: Jane Plover., Typescript (27pp.). (Box 7, Folder R)
  - Oswald., (9pp.). (Box 7, Folder R)
  - Stories: A True Adventure at Dawn., Typescript (8pp.). (Box 7, Folder R)
  - Recollections of A Walk Through France., Typescript (6pp.). (Box 7, Folder R)
  - The Story of A Spirit., Typescript carbon (14pp.). (Box 7, Folder R)
  - The True Tale of Mr. Boggs., (4pp.). (Box 7, Folder R)
  - Ephemera. News clippings., (3 items). (Box 8, Folder A)
  - Manuscript fragments: prose, poetry, indices., Manuscript and typescript (60pp.). (Box 8, Folder B)
  - Photographs of Harold Monro., (7 items). (Box 8, Folder C)
  - Poems. Miscellaneous., Typescript with corrections (17pp.). (Box 8, Folder D)
  - Poems, miscellaneous., In notebooks (2 items). (Box 8, Folder E)
  - Poems, articles, notes., In notebook (1 item). (Box 8, Folder F)
  - Before Dawn and A Book of Portraits. Poems in exercise book., (47pp.). (Box 8, Folder G)
  - Poems, unpublished., Typescript and manuscript (30pp.). (Box 8, Folder H)
  - Strange Meetings. Poems., (150pp.). (Box 8, Folder I)
    Some duplicate and early versions.